## **Dr Victor Maus**

Senior Researcher

**Curriculum Vitae** 

Juni 2021

**♀** Welthandelsplatz 1, 1020 Vienna, Austria

victor-maus.com

+43 1 31336 6176

vwmaus1@gmail.com

@victor\_maus

vwmaus

in victor-maus-083a79191

**G** wN2LseQAAAAJ&hl

**d** 0000-0002-7385-4723

I am a researcher in Geoinformatics and GIScience interested in environmental modeling and monitoring to understand drivers of global environmental change. My research has contributed to new methods for analyzing large satellite image data sets and help better understand the interactions between environment and human activities. I am experienced in IT, software development, management of servers and web services. To support my research, I have developed software and tools to visualize, handle and analyze large volumes of heterogeneous geodata, from statistical surveys to citizen science and satellite earth observations.

## **EDUCATION**

2016	<b>PhD in Earth System Science</b> São José dos Campos, Brazil	National Institute for Space Research (INPE)
2011	<b>MSc in Computational Modeling</b> Juiz de Fora, Brazil	Federal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF)
2009	<b>BSc in Environmental Engineering</b> Santa Maria, Brazil	Franciscan University (UFN)

## **CURRENT POSITIONS**

2018-	Senior Researcher	Vienna University of Economics and Business (WU)
	Vienna, Austria	
2016-	Research Scholar	International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis (IIASA)
	Laxenburg, Austria	

## **PREVIOUS POSITIONS**

2014-2016	<b>Research Assistant</b> Münster, Germany	University of Münster (WWU)
2012-2014	<b>University Lecturer</b> Itaqui, Brazil	Federal University of Pampa (UNIPAMPA)
2011-2012	<b>Research Assistant</b> São José dos Campos, Brazil	National Institute for Space Research (INPE)
2009-2011	<b>Research Assistant</b> Juiz de Fora, Brazil	Federal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF)

**FELLOWSHIPS AND AWARDS** SUPERVISION OF STUDENTS **TEACHING ACTIVITIES INSTITUTIONAL RESPONSIBILITIES REVIEWING ACTIVITIES PUBLICATIONS** 

- 1. Luckeneder, S., Giljum, S., Schaffartzik, A., Maus, V., & Tost, M. (2021). Surge in global metal mining threatens vulnerable ecosystems. Global Environmental Change, 69, 102303. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gloenvcha.2021. 102303
- 2. Maus, V., Giljum, S., Gutschlhofer, J., Silva, D. M. da, Gass, S. L. B., Luckeneder, S., Lieber, M., & McCallum, I. (2020). A global-scale data set of mining areas. Scientific Data, 7(1), 289. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-020-00624-w

- 3. Bruckner, M., Wood, R., Moran, D., Kuschnig, N., Wieland, H., **Maus, V.**, & Börner, J. (2019). FABIO-the construction of the food and agriculture biomass input-output model. *Environmental Science & Technology*, *53*(19), 11302–11312. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.9b03554
- 4. Stanimirova, R., Arévalo, P., Kaufmann, R. K., **Maus, V.**, Lesiv, M., Havlík, P., & Friedl, M. A. (2019). Sensitivity of global pasturelands to climate variation. *Earth's Future*. https://doi.org/10.1029/2019EF001316
- 5. Maus, V., Câmara, G., Appel, M., & Pebesma, E. (2019). dtwSat: Time-Weighted Dynamic Time Warping for Satellite Image Time Series Analysis in R. *Journal of Statistical Software*, 88(5), 1–31. https://doi.org/10.18637/jss.v088.i05
- 6. Bruckner, M., Häyhä, T., Giljum, S., **Maus, V**., Fischer, G., Tramberend, S., & Börner, J. (2019). Quantifying the global cropland footprint of the european union's non-food bioeconomy. *Environmental Research Letters*, 14(4), 045011. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ab07f5
- 7. Hadi, Krasovskii, A., **Maus, V.**, Yowargana, P., Pietsch, S., & Rautiainen, M. (2018). Monitoring Deforestation in Rainforests Using Satellite Data: A Pilot Study from Kalimantan, Indonesia. *Forests*, *9*(7). https://doi.org/10.3390/f9070389
- 8. See, L., Laso Bayas, J. C., Schepaschenko, D., Perger, C., Dresel, C., Maus, V., Salk, C., Weichselbaum, J., Lesiv, M., McCallum, I., Moorthy, I., & Fritz, S. (2017). LACO-Wiki: A New Online Land Cover Validation Tool Demonstrated Using GlobeLand30 for Kenya. *Remote Sensing*, 9(7). https://doi.org/10.3390/rs9070754
- 9. Furlan, V. J. M., **Maus, V**., Batista, I., & Bandarra, N. M. (2017). Production of docosahexaenoic acid by Auranti-ochytrium sp. ATCC PRA-276. *Brazilian Journal of Microbiology*, 48(2), 359–365. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bjm. 2017.01.001
- 10. **Maus, V.**, Camara, G., Cartaxo, R., Sanchez, A., Ramos, F. M., & Queiroz, G. R. de. (2016). A time-weighted dynamic time warping method for land-use and land-cover mapping. *IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing*, *9*(8), 3729–3739. https://doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2016.2517118
- 11. Furlan, V. J. M., Castelo Paulo, M. do, **Maus, V**., Ferreira, J., Batista, I., & Bandarrac, N. M. (2016). Production of docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) from Thraustochytrium sp. ATCC 26185 using different nitrogen concentrations. *Boletim Centro de Pesquisa de Processamento de Alimentos*, 34(2), 1–11. https://doi.org/10.5380/cep.v34i2. 53189
- See, L., Schepaschenko, D., Lesiv, M., McCallum, I., Fritz, S., Comber, A., Perger, C., Schill, C., Zhao, Y., Maus, V., Siraj, M. A., Albrecht, F., Cipriani, A., Vakolyuk, M., Garcia, A., Rabia, A. H., Singha, K., Marcarini, A. A., Kattenborn, T., ... Obersteiner, M. (2015). Building a hybrid land cover map with crowdsourcing and geographically weighted regression. ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 103, 48–56. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2014.06.016
- 13. **Maus, V.**, Costa, A. B. da, & Righes, A. A. (2009). Tratamento do lixiviado de aterro de resíduos sólidos urbanos por processo fenton. *Tecno-Lógica*, 13(1), 52–59. https://doi.org/10.17058/tecnolog.v13i1.931